MAHEDI KAISER

http://mahedikaiser.com mahedi.kaiser@gmail.com

347.925.4458

SUMMARY

Software engineer with over 5 years of experience and a track record for optimizing business processes through automation and innovation. Experience working in corporate and startup environments. Performed all roles in development including front-end, back-end, deployment/server management, and interfacing with business. A highly adaptable, passionate learner with a strong work ethic.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer New York, NY September 2018 – March 2019

Bombfell (Startup)

Payment System Rewrite (September 2018 – March 2019)

- Saved the company an average of 10% per refund transaction by fixing loophole in refund process
- Eliminated technical debt from payment system by refactoring and implementing test framework

Pagespeed Optimization (February 2019 – March 2019)

- Improved load time and search ranking by increasing Google Pagespeed score by 70 points (out of 100)
- Optimized Webpack resource loading using commons chunks and compression plugins
- Reorganized page structure and lazy-loaded below-the-fold contents

Security & Authentication (December 2018 – February 2019)

- Implemented Multi-factor Authentication for internal accounts
- Made accounts more brute-force resistant by implementing bcrypt password hashing

Bombfell Shop Launch (September 2018 – December 2018)

- Coordinated with Product Manager, Stylists, and 4 other developers to launch ecommerce shop in 2 months
- Wrote Server side code to search, sort, and cache shop items based on various filters and user preferences Custom Reporting Calendar (February 2019 March 2019)
 - Improved business utility of performance reports by designing and implementing custom calendar API based on Nation Retail Federation calendar and internally defined reporting periods

Software Engineer General Motors Detroit, MI

June 2016 – September 2018

Salesforce Rewrite Project (January 2018 – April 2018)

- Rewrote Salesforce APIs as in-house microservices to extend availability of services to more regions globally
- Collaborated with a team of 15 developers and architects to make microservices work together seamlessly
- Wrote comprehensive unit tests & integration tests to ensure code reliability and maintainability

Data Setup & Diagnostics Tool (February 2017 – September 2018)

- Cut defect resolution and data setup times by 30% by eliminating bottlenecks in the process
- Collaborated with a single teammate to design, develop & deploy the tool in under 6 months
- Minimized page load times by implementing Elasticsearch pipeline
- Used AJAX and wrote AngularJS plugins to provide fast, smooth, and intuitive user experience
- Handled all DevOps related tasks including deploying application to WebLogic, setting up SAML2 single sign on, and writing cron jobs to manage memory and monitor system health

Test Automation (June 2016 – September 2018)

- Responsible for creating automated tests for new Salesforce REST APIs using JUnit & Jenkins
- Improved readability and business utility of unit test results by migrating to Cucumber
- Minimized build failures by collaborating with multiple teams to resolve defects

SKILLS

Web Development ReactJS, AngularJS, NodeJS, JQuery, Bootstrap, WordPress, Weblogic, Webpack,

HTML, SASS, CSS

Programming Languages Java, Python, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL

Frameworks & Technologies Springboot, SQLAlchemy, Elasticsearch, Linux, JUnit, Cucumber

Tools Git, SVN, VIM, Eclipse, Intellij, Android Studios, Jenkins, Postman

Operating Systems Windows, Linux, Mac OSX

MAHEDI KAISER

http://mahedikaiser.com

Class of June 2016

mahedi.kaiser@gmail.com 347.925.4458

EDUCATION

Lehman College | BSc: Computer Science | GPA: 3.8

Dean's List (Fall 2014 – Spring 2015)

ADDITIONAL ACTIVITIES

Founder & Instructor Bronx, NY January 2019 – Present

Fullstack Engineering Bootcamp

 Developed and taught a comprehensive curriculum for fullstack development at my local community center aimed at anyone interested in learning software engineering

Mentored a wide range of students ranging from high school to post-college

Academic Excellence Chair

Bronx, NY

January 2016 - March 2016

National Society of Black Engineers

Organized workshops and study groups for computer science classes offered by Lehman college

Hosted resume reviews and interview preparation workshops for students seeking jobs and internships

2nd Place Winner Boston, MA March 2016

National Google Hackathon

• Worked with a team of 5 to create an android app to help drive up adoption rates by connecting prospective adopters with foster care children

1st Place Winner Bronx, NY October 2015

State-Wide NSBE Hackathon

• Worked with a team of 5 to create a mobile & web solution to connect people who need to give away their pets with prospective adopters with the purpose of keeping them out of kill shelters

• Independently developed a web app for the project using JavaScript to dynamically filter & display search results in addition to a second webpage to serve as a demo for the application

Mathematics Researcher & Programmer

Bronx, NY

October 2015 - January 2016

CUNY- Research Foundation

• Worked in groups to come up with algorithms to compute shortest paths in CAT(k) space with direct application to mapping optimal evolutionary history in phylogenetic trees

• Wrote Python code to implement proposed solutions